# **Vincent Varghese**

Covington, WA 98042

Phone: 516 384 4461 | Email: VinAVarghese@gmail.com

Linkedin: https://www.linkedin.com/in/vincent-varghese

Portfolio: https://vav-portfolio.herokuapp.com/ | GitHub: https://github.com/VinAVarghese

#### Summary

A Full Stack Developer leveraging over five years of management experience to produce meaningful outputs while cultivating healthy team dynamics. Fluent in HTML, CSS, JavaScript and the full MERN stack with a full-stack development certificate from the University of Washington. Known among peers for strengthening teams and producing successful deliverables.

#### **Technical Skills**

JavaScript	Node.js	Git
JSON	Express	Responsive Design
AJAX	MongoDB	<b>User Authentication</b>
React.js	mySQL	Progressive Web Apps

#### **Projects**

#### PLANIT | GitHub https://tinyurl.com/yyr4x2jr | Link https://tinyurl.com/yxfigl36

- PLANIT is a collaborative, group trip planner.
- Led front-end development using React. Developed creative assets and directed UX/UI.
- Tools: Ant Design, React.js, React-animate-on-scroll, React-scroll, MongoDB

#### MixMe | GitHub https://tinyurl.com/yx9tevn6 | Link https://tinyurl.com/y598ysr2

- MixMe is a web application that searches drink recipes by ingredients.
- Led front-end development, created responsive layouts, creative assets and UX/UI.
- Tools: Foundation, CSSShake, JSON and AJAX

## Spontaneously Now | GitHub https://tinyurl.com/yy2rqxny | Link https://tinyurl.com/y22c6alr

- Spontaneously Now is a web application that suggests random activities with a chosen category and allows for note taking for planning and journaling about activity
- Led back-end development, integrating four 3rd-party APIs with our mySQL database.
  Developed creative assets and directed UX/UI.
- Tools: Foundation, CSSAnimate, Sequelize, Express, Moment, Handlebars, AXIOS, and AJAX

## **Experience**

Consultant2020 – 2020The Church CoRemote

Providing customer satisfaction with excellent website setup via Wordpress

## **Acting District Manager**

2019 - 2019

CityMD Seattle, WA

- Successfully led 8 urgent care clinics during a company transition
- Maintained excellent Press Ganey scores and reviews from patients during transition

**Site Manager** 2018 – 2019

CityMD Seattle, WA

- Was directly responsible for clinic's customer service experience and produced the top
  Press Ganey scores in the region for customer satisfaction
- Entrusted with additional responsibility of tracking and submitting staff's DOH licensing

# **Assistant Site Manager**

2017 - 2018

CityMD Seattle, WA

• Trusted by Regional Manager to solely preform Site Manager duties for six months to help the company during a staff transition

## **Information & Public Awareness Manager**

2014 - 2016

Vision Rescue Mumbai, MH, India

- Increased social media engagement from no activity to a global presence
- Created and oversaw a reporting system to relay on-field impact data to partners
- Recruited and liaised local and international partnerships, effectively presenting to corporate boards and larger auditoriums

#### Education

Bootcamp Certificate: University of Washington, Seattle, WA

A 12-week intensive program focused on gaining technical programming skills in HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, JQuery, Bootstrap, Node.js, MySQL, MongoDB, Express, Handelbars.js, and React

Bachelors Degree: Alphacrucis College, Sydney, NSW, Australia

A Bachelors in Contemporary Ministry, focusing on leadership. Upon graduating, received the "Outstanding Graduate Award: Exemplary Achievement & Leadership"